Slavick, Frederick, Papers /3037
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frederick Slavick Papers
1949-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Slavick, Frederick
/3037
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Papers mostly regarding Globe Forge and Foundry, Syracuse, NY, labor and healthcare.
3074590
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, July 01, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 21, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Slavick (July 2, 1923 August 5, 1999) was a professor at Cornell University's School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A veteran of World War II, Slavick completed his BA and MA at University of Wisconsin- Madison (in 1946 and 1947, respectively). He completed his PhD in Economics at Princeton University in 1953, and joined the Cornell faculty in the same year. A Research Associate when he first arrived at Cornell, he was promoted to Assistant Professor in 1954, Associate Professor in 1960, and full Professor in 1966. He retired from the faculty of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1978.
Slavick worked at the Bureau of Labor and Management in the College of Commerce at the State University of Iowa for two years and published works relating to labor in Iowa, including "Voluntary Quits in Iowa" in Labor Law Journal 10:5 (May1959) and, with Jack F. Culley, "Employment Problems of Older Workers" as part of the Bureau's Informational Series (No. 1, 1959). He also published on retirement, insurance, and benefit plans for workers.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Frederick Slavick: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/17972
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4016: Frederick Slavick Retirement Study Files
Slavick, Fred.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3074590
- Interviews with Hospital Administrators and Correspondence with, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence on Interviews with Syn-Doctors and Hospitals, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Physicians to be called from Appointments, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Interviews with Radiologists and other M.D.'s, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Carrier 1st, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Globe Forge, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Globe Forge Maternity Cases, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Globe Forge, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Analysis of Globe Forge claims, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Directions for IBM Computations - Globe Forge Code, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lithographers, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Interviews, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Company v. Union Contracts for Health Insurance Study, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Syracuse Manufacturing Company, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Notes and Materials for Health Insurance Study, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Prof. Lanson's Questionnaires and Comments on Study, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Lithographers Questionnaire, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Authorizations by Lithographers to Hartford, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Globe Forge - Elec. Case Exp., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Carrier, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Straight-Line Friendly, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Catherwood, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Catherwood, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Outline Distributed, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence - Health Insurance Study, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Globe Forge, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Straight Line Foundry, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Sam De Mauro - Vice President, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Globe Forge, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Carrier, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Proposed New Crouse-Swing Hospital Syracuse, N.Y., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Proposed New Crouse-Swing Hospital Syracuse, N.Y., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)